CURRICULAM VITAE

Ajim Hajimalang Shaikh

Mechanical Design Engineer (Creo, Pro-E, Diesel Engine Component Design)

azeemshaikh24@gmail.com

Mobile: 9881039697 Local Address:

B6, Pavaneshwar colony,

Thergaon gavthan,

Thergaon, Pune-411033

CAREER OBJECTIVE:-

A Challenging career in a company with a good working environment, progressive approach and performance based growth, where I can use my skills to contribute to the growth of the company.

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY:-

Design Engineer having 4.9 years experience of Design & development. Also having 1.3 years experience of Quality Assurance in automotive sectors. Currently working in KPIT Technologies Ltd. Having experience of Design, New Project Development, Planning.

COMPUTER SKILLS:-

PRO-E WF 4.0/5.0	CREO 2.0/3.0
Solid	Solid
Modeling	Modeling
Assembly / Mechanism	Assembly / Mechanism
Drafting	Drafting
Engine layout	Engine layout

CORE COMPETENCIES:-

- Domain Skills Automotive (Engine & sub system), Casting, Sheet metal and Hydraulics (Pro-piping).
- Design Tools Creo Parametric 3.0.
- PLM Tools Wind-chill, Matrix 10.1, PDM link and Nexus IMS.
- Knowledge of Geometric Dimensioning & Tolerance (GD&T) and ASME standards.
- Knowledge of Tolerance Stack-Up Analysis, DFMEA

INDUSTRIAL EXPERIENCE:-

➤ Working as Design Engineer in **KPIT Technologies Ltd.**

From Nov 2017 to till date.

❖ ROLE & RESPONSIBILITIES:-

• Design, Re-engineering, concept modeling and detailing of various casting and sheet metal components of Engine and engine sub-system, make necessary changes as per the requirement in the existing/New models of Diesel Engines.

- Designing & modifying components with respect to Customer requirements, CAE reports and testing reports.
- Analyzing customer requirements & providing solutions.

➤ PROJECTS :-

Cummins Engine business unit, UK Daventry

- Modeling and Detailing of engine related casting parts like inlet manifold, exhaust manifold, Flywheel housing & rocker cover.
- Concept modeling & detailing of Sheet metal Brackets.
- Modeling & detailing of Pro-Piping, Tubes, Flexible Hoses.
- Engine sub assemblies drawing.

➤ Design Engineer in **GREAVES COTTON LTD.**

Onsite from Expert global Pvt. Ltd. Pune

From Jan 2015 to Oct 2017

- ❖ DEPARTMENT: R & D Department.
- **❖** <u>RESPONSIBILITIES:</u>-
 - Engine layouts and concept modeling in Pro-E 5 & creo 3.0
 - Tolerance stack up, calculation and DFMEA.
 - Make modeling of engine components like Crankcase, Crankshaft, Camshaft, Oil sump, Exhaust bellow, Inlet manifold, exhaust manifold Gear casing, rocker cover, brackets, adaptor.
 - Making GA (General Arrangement) drawing of Engine.
 - Make drawing Crank Case, cylinder head, front cover, manifold, assembly drawings.
 - Make modeling & drafting of jacketed leak off pipe, combine leak off pipe, fuel collector arrangement, high pressure pipes, crank pulley casting & m/c, fuel pump layout, suction tube with assembly, sump oil capacity & pitching, rolling lay outing.
 - New release drawing &.Releasing the modified drawing.
 - Upload all data of Wind-chill 11 and all release process.
 - Create new Bill of material total **Engine Assembly** with group wise.
 - Making ISPL of Engine.

❖ PROJECTS:-

- Development of 3G, 4G and 6G VAVE ENGINES.
- Development of D3V6 and D3V8 CPCB-II ENGINES.
- Development of 12V14TAG 2100 RPM 500 kVA ENGINE.
- Development of fuel piping of RCF engines.
- Development of Marine engine.

> Design Engineer in Involute Technologies pvt. Ltd, Pune.

From july.2013 to Dec 2014

❖ <u>RESPONSIBILITIES</u> :-

- Creating Sheet metal, Casting component models, Assemblies and drawings by using PRO/E5.0 as a CAD tool.
- Developing gears and transmission shafts as per supplier requirements.
- Converting customer drawing in to manufacturing drawing
- Creating and modifications of existing component drawings according to requirements of customer.
- Conversion of 2D drawings of 3D model.
- Design of fixture according to the requirement.
- Creating Fabrication drawings using Proe 5.0.

❖ PROJECTS :-

- Development of Caterpillar shafts and assemblies
- Development of Turner Drive Trains shafts and assemblies
- Development of poclain Hydraulics shafts.
- Development of John Deere transmission gears and shafts.
- ➤ Trainee Engineer in Automotive Metal Stamping pvt. Ltd. March 2012 to June 2013
 - **❖** <u>DEPARTMENT:</u> **Quality Assurance.**
 - **❖** RESPONSIBILITIES:-
 - PPAP Documentations (Control plan, FMEA,PFD& SPC)
 - In process inspection & final inspection.
 - Interfaces with engineering, customers and suppliers.
 - Conduct dock audit, Process audit.
 - Standards for welding processes etc standard documents preparation.

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION:-

Exam Passed	Institute Name	Passing Year	University	Percentage	Division
B.E (Mech)	TPCT's College of Engg. Osmanabad	May 2011	Dr.B.A.M.U.	62.26%	First class
HSC	SVMP Pangri	March 2005	PUNE	63.83%	First class
SSC	SVMP Pangri	March 2003	PUNE	75.33%	Distinction

STRENGTH:-

- ➤ Better grasping power.
- Ability to manage time, Convert Hard work to Smart Work,
- Willingness to learn.

PERSONAL DETAILS:-

Name : Ajim Hajimalang Shaikh.

Date of Birth : 24 Aug 1987 Marital Status : Married.

Languages Known : Marathi, English and Hindi.

Hobbies : Playing Cricket, Listening Music, Watching TV, chatting with friends.

Permanent Address : A/P - Pangri, Tal - Barshi, Dist - Solapur

Maharashtra. Pin-413404

DECLARATION:-

I hereby declare that the above-mentioned information is correct up to my knowledge and I bear the responsibility for the correctness of the above-mentioned particulars.

Date: / / 2018

Place: Pune

AJIM HAJIMALANG SHAIKH.